Guide to the Walter Wilson Greg Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Working Papers, BEPD, Volumes I-II, 1939-1954; Series XII; 0.83; (2 boxes)
  Material is arranged in no particular order.
  Photostats, facsimiles, notes and other working materials for the BEPD, many annotated and numbered by Greg.
  - Working materials for vols. 1-11 of BEPD - including comparative photostats of title pages, lists of players, portraits of authors in facsimile and photostat; various textual notes by WWG. [N.B. many items bear numbers corresponding to their places in the final BEPD .] (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Facsimile of "Good Order: A morality fragment: [cf. Frost and Nash Studies in Philology v. XLI n. 4, Box 2, Folder 1; cf BEPD v. 3 p. 1540, v. 4 p. 1643]. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Photostats for "Prefaces and Such" (1954). Many bear BEPD numbers. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Memoranda to accompany Greg's proofs for BEPD vol. 1 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Photostats of title pages showing Dramatis Personae for BEPD entries. [Many bear BEPD numbers.] (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - "The Enterlude of the IIII Cardinal Vertues" (1541-1547) photostats. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - "Gentleness and Nobility" (?1529) photostats. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - "Beggar's Bush" (1647) photostats. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - "Beggar's Bush" photostats (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - "The Humorous Lieutenant" photostats. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - MSS "Addresses of Stationers in imprints in "A Bibliography of English Printed Drama" v. I [Greg's record of stationers]. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - "Henry IIII" (1599) Epistle dedictory photostats. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous working notes for BEPD. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - The Duchess of Malfy (1623) photostats. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Bird in a Cage (1633) photostats. (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Working papers, projects other than BEPD, 1940-1956, undated; Series XIII; 0.21; (1 box)
  Notes, transcriptions and annotated photocopies pertaining to various editorial and research projects by Greg.
  - Papers and photostats pertaining to Doctor Faustus, including listing of B2 variants. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - MS of "Biographical notes 1875-1947" [cf Box 1 Fol 3] (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - "Henslowe's Diary" photostats of Frag. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - "A Pretye Complaynt of Peace" (1538?) photostats (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - "Joyes of Maryage"(?) and "Of Marriage and Wiving" photostats. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous MS photostats B.M. MS ADD. 18920 fol. 140a-141a, B.M. MS Landsdowne 807 fol. 1, unknown stationer's register. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Miscellanous printed matter photostats: Orlando Furioso 1584 and 1591; History of Philos, The Lives of the Noble Grecians and Romans. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Notes for Collected Papers [also notes by J.C. Maxwell]. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - MS Transcription: Richard Mulcaster to Sir Julius Caesar 1605 November 25 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - MS listing of papers read at Cambridge University English Society 1896-1898. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous MS notes by Greg, others. (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Photostats, Manuscript and printed, undated; Series XIV; 0.84; (3 boxes)
  Photostats of manuscript and printed texts used by Greg during his research.
  - Injunctions Given By The Queen Majesty (1539) [From B.M. C. 122 C. 1 (1)] (Box 13)
  - The Masque of Queens (1609) [B.M. MSRoyal 18 A XLV] [ALS, Percy Simpson to WW Greg laid in] (Box 13)
  - Parts of one actor in three miracle plays [Shrewsbury School MS Mus. III 4z] [ALS from P.W. Pilcher and J.B. Oldham; LS from William M. How Laid In]. (Box 13)
  - "Dux Moraud" and other poems; in MS (H.C.) [Bod. MS Eng. Poetry f. 2 (r) 30519] [ALS from F.P. Wilson Laid In]. (Box 13)
  - Henry IV part I (Frag). (Box 13)
  - Processus Satanae, The part of God in a miracle play (c. 1570-1580) [2 ALS from Francis Needham Laid In]. (Box 13)
  - Listing of books for sale, Simon Miller (ca. 1653-1684) [not photostat]. (Box 13)
  - Various photostats, unsorted. (Box 14)
  - Various photostats, unsorted. (Box 15)
- Appendix: Listing of Correspondence enclosed in volumes
  General note
  This is a list of letters located in volumes cataloged separately. Location and subject notes are given for most items.
  - Adams, Joseph Quincy, 1881-1946
    ALS to WW Greg
    1929 August 10, Ithaca, NY
    location: f. pe 12
    Remarks on Tannenbaum's Book on
    The Revels
  - Alexander, R.D.
    1929 September 18, Glasgow
    location: pe 219
  - Baldwin, Thomas Witfield, 1890-
    LS to WW Greg
    1931 October 31, London
    location: pe 231
    Note on Percy Plays
  - Bartlett, Henrietta Collins, 1873-1963
    location: pe 234
    1946 September 17, Old Lyme, Conn.
  - Bentley, Gerald Eades, 1901-
    1941 September 1, Chicago
    location: pe 324
    Offers aid for BED v. II
  - Bradley, Henry, 1845-1923
    1910 August 29. Oxford
    location: pd 187
    Remarks on printing symbol
    1910 November 12, Oxford
  - Brooke, Charles Frederick Tucker
    1933 October 27, New Haven
    location: pe 268
    Note on text of Mucedorus
  - Chambers, Sir Edmund Kerchever, 1866-1954
    1938 January 16, Oxford
    location: pd 188
  - Chambers, Raymond WiIson, 1874-1942
    1937 April 13, Southgate
    location: pe 226
    1940 November 6, London
    location: Box 2 item 4
  - Crow, John
    1956 May 7, London
    location: pe 289
    Notes on text of Richard II 1956 May 23, London
    location: pe 265
    Remarks on Black's R2
  - Davin, Daniel Marcus, 1913-
    1953 January 27, Oxford
    location: pe 230
    Note on K. Sisam's book
    1958 August 25, Oxford
    location: pe 286
    1959 January 23, Oxford
    location: pe 228
    Note on R.B. McKerrow
  - Davis, Herbert John, 1893-
    1958 November Oxford
    location: pe 239
    Presentation note
  - Dawson, Giles Edwin, 1903-
    1956 August 27, Washington
    location: pe 312
    Notes on The Troublesome Reign
  - Day, Mabel Katherine
    1940 August 20, London
    location: pe 224
  - Duthie, George Ian
    1953 September 20, Montreal
    location: pe 216
  - Feuillerat, Albert, 1874-
    1905 September 21, Bayswater
    location: pe 328
    1905 September 23, Bayswater
    1905 November 15, Rennes, France
  - Francis, Sir Frank Charlton, 1901-
    undated, London
  - Fry, Mary Isabel
    1956 August 28, San Marino
    1957 May 13, San Marino
    Notes on text of Richard III
  - Gibson, L.
    1936 June 20, Oxford
    location: pe 336
    1936 June 23, Oxford
    Enclosure wanting
  - Hanson, W.W.
    1956 July 19, Oxford
    location: pe 309
    Note on The First Part of Contention
  - Hoenifel, F.D.
    1957 May 19, London
    location: pe 293
    Queries on Pericles text
  - Hoppe, Harry Reno, 1906-
    1944 March 21, East Lansing, Mich.
    Off-print enclosed
    1946 August 24, East Lansing, Mich.
    location: pe 265 John of Bordeaux article remarks
    1947 January 22, Brussels
  - Howard, Arthur
    1956 June 16, Wappingthorn, Steyning
    Textual notes in Henry IV part 2.
  - Huntington, Henry Edwards, 1850-1927
    LS to Deighton, Bell and Co.
    location: pe 236
    1920 June 9, San Marino
  - Kellner, Leon, 1859-
    1924 January 24, Vienna
    location: pe 258
    Remarks on Massinger corrections
    1925 October 2l, Benjamina Station, Palestine
    Response to Greg's review
  - Macauley, George Campbell, 1852-1915
    undated, Cambridge
  - McKerrow, Ronald Brunlees, 1872-1940
    undated
    Textual observations on Morte Arthur MS
  - Marvin, Allen
    1942 April 31, London
  - Maxwell, J.C.
    1952 December 6, Newcastle Upon Tyne
    location: pe 272
    Textual issues in ?; enclosure wanting
    1952 December 15, Newcastle Upon Tyne
    1954 September 3, Newcastle Upon Tyne
    Response to Greg's review of Titus Andronicus (copy enclosed)
  - Mead, Herman
    1956 May 31, San Marino
  - Needham, Francis
    1931 April 29, Worksop, Notts
    location: Box 14 Processus Satanae Enclosure wanting
    1931 May 1, Worksop, Notts
  - Nicholson, [Frank Carr?]
    1934 August 1, Edinburgh
    location: pe 301
    Textual notes on Titus Andronicus
  - Nixon, Howard M.
    1954 February 23, London
    location: pe 211
    STC listings
    1954 April 20, London
    STC-BM correspondence
  - Oates, John Claud Trenchard
    1955 October 14, Cambridge
    Reviewing J.K. Walton's Folio Text of King Lear location: pe 326
  - Pafford, J.W.
    1953 November 19, London
    Remarks on word vamper (s)
  - Parrod, A.M.
    1937 January 27, Boulder, Colo.
    location: pe 235
  - Parsons, John Denham
    1935 July 20, Chiswick
    location: pe 316
    Remarks following Greg's comments on R. Field and the First Shakespeare Poem 1935 Jul 24, Chiswick
    1935 July 31, Chiswick
    Remarks following postcard from Greg
  - Pollard, Alfred William, IS59-1944
    Notes on A Midsummer Night's Dream location: pe 276
    Sunday (undated), Wimbledon
    2 p. remarks on Malone Leir ALS Frag. to [WW Greg?]
  - Simpson, Andrew
    undated, Salisbury
    Note on priest in "Oldcastle"
  - Simpson, Percy, 1865-1962
    1921 September 19, Oxford
    1937 March 29, Oxford
    Response to review of Proofreading in the Sixteenth Seventeenth and Eighteenth Centuries location: pe 336
  - Sisam, Kenneth
    1941 August 22, Oxford
    1958 December 20, St. Mary's Isles of Scilly
  - Smith, Robert Metcalf, 1886
    1928 March 7, Bethlehem, PA
    location: pe 250
    Remarks on variants in Second Folio
  - Smith, S.C. Moore
    location: Box 1 Folder 2 item 7
  - Stamp, Alfred Edward, 1870-
    1929 June 17, London
    Results of ink investigation
    location: f pe 12
    1930 November 17
  - Walker, Alice
    1953 August 26, Bideford, Devon
    location: pe 217
  - Walton, James Kirkwood
    1957 October 13, Dublin
    location: pe 326
    Remarks on relation of Shakespeare texts
    1958 February 11, Dublin
    "The Quarto Copy for the Folio
    Richard III" enclosed
  - Wilson, Frank Pierce, 1889-1963
    November 27, Northampton, Mass.
    location: pe 332
    1955 January 17, Oxford
    Parallel passages in The Troublesome Reign of King John
  - Wilson, John Dover
    1943 October 23, Balerno, Midlothian
    location: pe 248
    Remarks following comments on Falstaff 1944 June 6, Balerno, Midlothian
    Reports death of son
    1946 July 31
    1949 January 22, Balerno, Midlothian
    Textual issues in Antony and Cleopatra location: pe 323
    1957 December 21, Balerno, Midlothian
    Remarks on Walton's Folio text paper
    (copy of letter to Walton enclosed)
  - Wright, J. Aldis
    1900 March 23, Cambridge
    1906 April 5, Beccles, Suffolk
  - Wright, Lyle Henry, 1903
    1956 July 10, San Marino
    Notes on Text of Richard II
  - Yule, George Undy, 1871-
    1944 October 23, Cambridge
    location: pe 260
    Thanks for Greg's Review of his Study of Literary Vocabulary